
export const quizQuestions_8 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'In React, what is the primary function of the useState hook in functional components?',
      choices: ['To manage component’s local state', 'To handle HTTP requests', 'To create side effects in components', 'To manipulate the DOM'],
      correctAnswer: 'To manage component’s local state',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How can you pass a function as a prop to a functional component in React?',
      choices: ['<Component onClick={myFunction} />', '<Component function={myFunction()} />', '<Component function="myFunction" />', 'Functions cannot be passed as props'],
      correctAnswer: '<Component onClick={myFunction} />',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the main difference between state and props in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['State is mutable, props are immutable', 'Props are mutable, state is immutable', 'There is no difference', 'State is for UI, props are for data'],
      correctAnswer: 'State is mutable, props are immutable',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'Why is it important to use a key when rendering a list of elements in React?',
      choices: ['For unique identification of elements', 'To improve rendering performance', 'For styling purposes', 'Both for unique identification of elements and to improve rendering performance'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both for unique identification of elements and to improve rendering performance',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What does the term “lifting state up” mean in React?',
      choices: ['Moving state to a higher-level component', 'Storing state in a global context', 'Increasing the size of the state', 'Optimizing state for better performance'],
      correctAnswer: 'Moving state to a higher-level component',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of using React.memo in a functional component?',
      choices: ['To store data in memory', 'To prevent unnecessary re-renders', 'To memoize component methods', 'To enable memory management in React'],
      correctAnswer: 'To prevent unnecessary re-renders',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'In a functional component, how is a component’s lifecycle managed?',
      choices: ['Using lifecycle methods like componentDidMount', 'Through hooks like useEffect', 'Lifecycle management is not available in functional components', 'Using global state management'],
      correctAnswer: 'Through hooks like useEffect',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the main benefit of destructuring props in a functional component?',
      choices: ['To increase the component’s rendering speed', 'For cleaner and more readable code', 'Destructuring props is not allowed in functional components', 'To avoid passing props to children components'],
      correctAnswer: 'For cleaner and more readable code',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How do you handle default values for missing props in a functional component?',
      choices: ['Using defaultProps', 'By using a default case in a switch statement', 'Default values are not supported in functional components', 'By initializing state with props'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using defaultProps',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'In React, how can functional components communicate with each other?',
      choices: ['Directly calling methods of other components', 'Through passing props from parent to child components', 'Using global variables', 'Functional components cannot communicate with each other'],
      correctAnswer: 'Through passing props from parent to child components',
    },
    
  ],
}